<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Singpro</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-11-20T09:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Open seminar by Dr. Pedro Castro</title><link href="/seminar-castro.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-20T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-11-20T09:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Singpro Team.</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-11-20:/seminar-castro.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Third SINGPRO open seminar at Aalto University.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We had the pleasure to host Dr. Pedro Castro (University of Lisbon, Portugal) at Aalto University for a week in November. During the visit, Dr. Castro gave an open seminar, entitled "Optimization Models for Scheduling in the Process Industries".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract: Scheduling is a key element in enterprise-wide optimization, which concerns optimizing the supply, manufacturing and distribution activities of a company. Scheduling problems typically deal with time horizons of days or weeks and are typically tackled using mixed-integer linear (MILP) or nonlinear (MINLP) models. One of the challenges in scheduling is the wide variety of problems that can be found, which has hindered the development of a model/algorithm/commercial software that is both general and computationally efficient. Nevertheless, major developments have occurred over the last 30 years in the Process Systems Engineering community, which will be briefly reviewed. Examples include the unified frameworks for process representation (State- and Resource-Task Network), discrete- and continuous-time formulations, and the use of Generalized Disjunctive Programming to help formulating difficult constraints. We will then discuss 6 eal-life problems from the chemical and petroleum industry. They deal with time-dependent electricity costs, heat integration in batch plants, transportation of liquids by pipeline, refinery planning and crude oil blending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The slides of the seminar can be found &lt;a href="/2019-11-20-PedroCastro.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="research visit"></category><category term="seminars"></category><category term="scheduling"></category></entry><entry><title>3rd SINGPRO Seminar (November 19, 2019)</title><link href="/seminar-03.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-19T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-11-19T09:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Singpro Team.</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-11-19:/seminar-03.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Third SINGPRO open seminar at Aalto University.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the third seminar was to present the main contributions of the project and the open challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The slides of the seminar can be found &lt;a href="/2019-11-19-SINGPRO-seminar-slides.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="third"></category><category term="seminars"></category></entry><entry><title>2nd SINGPRO Seminar (April 17, 2019)</title><link href="/seminar-02.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-17T09:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-17T09:00:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Singpro Team.</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-04-17:/seminar-02.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Second SINGPRO open seminar at Aalto University.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The topics of our second seminar were 1) big data platforms for machine learning applications, 2) causality discovery Approach for nonlinear time series, and 3) efficient and systematic production scheduling formulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The slides of the seminar can be found &lt;a href="/2019-04-17-SINGPRO-seminar-slides.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="second"></category><category term="seminars"></category></entry><entry><title>1st SINGPRO Seminar (October 15, 2018)</title><link href="/seminar-01.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-15T09:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-10-15T13:00:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Singpro Team.</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-10-15:/seminar-01.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;First SINGPRO open seminar at Aalto University.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the seminar was to introduce the project to our academic and industrial
partners, present early research results and open a platform for discussion of problems and solutions
in industrial processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The slides of the seminar can be found &lt;a href="/SINGPRO-2018-10-15.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="first"></category><category term="seminars"></category></entry></feed>