<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Singpro - research</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/research.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2018-10-15T13:00:00+03:00</updated><entry><title>Synergistic and intelligent process optimization (SINGPRO)</title><link href="/research-01.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-15T09:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-10-15T13:00:00+03:00</updated><author><name>Singpro Team.</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-10-15:/research-01.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;First SINGPRO open seminar at Aalto University.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;SINGPRO merges Big Data platforms, machine learning and data analytics methods with process
planning and scheduling optimization. The project, funded by academy of Finland, is a collaborative
effort between Aalto University (Professor Iiro Harjunkoski, Department of Chemical and Metallurgical
Engineering) and the University of Helsinki (Professor Keijo Heljanko, Department of Computer
Science).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the project is to create online, reactive and anticipative tools for more sustainable and
efficient operation leading to an agile, self-aware and flexible decision-making loop. SINGPRO will
enable the tracking of abnormal situations (i.e. anomaly detection), identifying process equipment
performance degradations (i.e. predictive maintenance) and anticipate process timing deviations (i.e.
process behavior prediction). This helps to select the best production strategies in order to maintain
production and energy efficiency as well as sustainability targets in rapidly changing market situations
through data-driven self-adaptive scheduling models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have held our first open seminar for the project at Aalto University on the 15th of October 2018 
between 9-11am. We thank everyone who joined the seminar either physically or over the internet.
The purpose of the seminar was to introduce the project to our academic and industrial
partners, present early research results and open a platform for discussion of problems and solutions
in industrial processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The schedule and the materials presented at the seminar can be found below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9:00 – 9:30 Coffee
9:30 – 9:45 Introduction to the SINGPRO project (Adj. Prof. Iiro Harjunkoski)
9:45 – 10:05 Machine learning for predictive maintenance (Dr. Tewodros Deneke)
10:05 – 10:25 Parameter prediction and realization in job shop scheduling: A Gaussian process
approach (Dr. Teemu Ikonen)
10:25 – 10:45 Open discussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the slide that contains all the three presentations at the seminar form &lt;a href="/SINGPRO-2018-10-15.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="first"></category><category term="research"></category></entry></feed>